bonpay.com 2018-12-31

# Policies and Terms of Service - Bonpay - Bonpay

## GENERAL INFORMATION

Bon Solutions LP, registered in Scotland with No. SL023523, (registered office: 75 King William St, London, EC4N 7BE, UK) (“BONPAY”, “We”, “Us”, or “Our”) has established this Privacy Policy Statement to assist you to understand how we collect and use personally identifiable information if and when you use our website as a “Visitor” or provide information to us in connection with your use of the Service as a “User”.

 **We encourage you to read the information below carefully.**

By using our website at www.bonpay.com and our Services, you agree to the collection, use and processing of your personal data in the manner described in this Privacy Policy. By registering for our Service, you agree to the collection and use of personal information in the manner described in this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use. This Privacy Policy applies to the Mobile Application and website regardless of how you access or use them.

You accept this Privacy Policy when you sign up for, access, or use our products, services, features, technologies or functions offered on our website and mobile application (collectively “Service”). This Privacy Policy is intended to govern the use of Service by our users (including, without limitation those who use the Service in the course of their trade or business) unless otherwise agreed through contract. This Privacy Policy is an essential part of the Terms of Use.

Storing, processing and transferring of Personal Data by Bonpay is performed within the Services provided by Bonpay.

If you do not agree to the terms set out in these policies, please do not continue to use our website.

We may update or amend this Privacy Policy at any time by posting a revised version on our website and sending a notification to our Users via email. You understand and agree that if we send You a message, but You do not receive it because of not updating Your email address, Bonpay will be deemed to have provided the message to you. The revised version will be effective as of the published effective date or as of the date directly stated in the amended Privacy Policy.

The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to ensure that Bonpay complies with applicable regulations valid in the European Union and the United Kingdom.

## DATA CONTROLLER

For the purposes of the EU General Data Protection Regulation, effective 25.05.2018 (hereinafter – GDPR), Bon Solutions LP is the data controller of a User’s personal data when it provides the User with Services or information related to the Services.

## YOUR PERSONAL DATA PROCESSING

According to the GDPR,

 **‘Personal data’** means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person; an identifiable natural person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person.

We do not consider personal data to include information that has been anonymized so that it does not identify You, as a specific User.

In this section we provide you with the information about personal data we collect, the way we collect and use it, and our lawful basis for personal data processing.

### 1\. Your identification and contact details

Bonpay processes your personal information that you provide to us: your name, surname, date of birth, gender, nationality and/or citizenship, residential address, email address, and telephone number.

 **We use your personal data for the following purposes:**

  * to provide the Services and customer support;
  * to administer and process your application for Bonpay account;
  * to administer and maintain our Users’ accounts and records;
  * to measure the performance of the Services and improve their content and layout;
  * to communicate with you by placing a voice call or text (SMS) at your telephone number or by email and collect your feedback;
  * to send personalised offers of Services;
  * to contact you to inform you about the Services and as necessary to enforce our policies, fees, applicable law, or any agreement we may have with you.

 **We rely on the following lawful bases for personal data processing:**

  * it is necessary to enter into, perform and/or fulfill a contract or an agreement with you;
  * it is our legitimate interest to managing and administering our Services;
  * it is our legitimate interest to provide the Services to our clients;
  * it is our legitimate interest to promote our Services, and personalize the information that our website sends to you. If required under applicable law, we will not send you marketing communications unless you first consent to this. You can withdraw such consent at any time by changing your account preferences or contacting us at support@bonpay.com. You cannot refuse to receive notification about Bonpay Services or policies changing or updating as it is Bonpay’s legal obligation to provide you with such information.

### 2\. Know Your Customer (KYC) information

Bonpay processes your personal data and documents provided by you as the proof of indicated information. Bonpay may also collect KYC information from the third parties or from the public sources. KYC information includes:

  * your photo;
  * passport or other government-issued identity document;
  * documents proving your residential address;
  * documents establishing your source of funds or source of wealth;
  * results of KYC or Politically Exposed Person (PEP) checks, including information collected by our service providers;
  * sensitive information revealing your religious, political or philosophical beliefs, relating to offences (or alleged offences), your ethnic background, about your health, trade union membership or sex life or sexual orientation as needed.

 **We use your personal data for the following purposes:**

  * to provide the Services and customer support;
  * to administer and maintain our Users’ accounts and records;
  * to verify your identity, including during account creation and password reset processes;
  * to manage risk, or to detect, prevent, and/or remediate fraud, money laundering, terrorist financing, offences involving identity theft or other potentially prohibited or illegal activities;
  * to detect, prevent or remediate violations of policies or applicable user agreements;
  * to carry out regulatory checks and meet out obligations to our regulators;
  * to comply with our regulatory obligations to conduct KYC which may sometimes reveal sensitive information.

 **We rely on the following lawful bases for personal data processing:**

  * it is necessary to enter into, perform and/or fulfill a contract or an agreement with you;
  * you have provided us with your consent to use your personal information, including sensitive information, for this purpose;
  * it is our legitimate interest to manage and administer our Services;
  * we are legally required to do so under the UK law;
  * it is our legitimate interest to protect our business against damage, fraud or possible criminal acts;
  * it is necessary for reasons of substantial public interest under the UK law, and/or we have taken measures to safeguard your rights.

### 3\. Financial information

Bonpay stores, monitors, records and uses your financial information relating to your using of Bonpay Services that may include:

  * your Bonpay wallet balance;
  * your Bonpay card information and balance;
  * your transactions details, including virtual currency transactions;
  * used currencies;
  * full bank accounts numbers that you link to your Bonpay account or give us when using our Services.

 **We use your personal data for the following purposes:**

  * to provide the Services and customer support;
  * to administer and maintain our Users’ accounts and records;
  * to administer and maintain our Services and systems;
  * to process transactions and send notices about your transactions;
  * to resolve disputes and troubleshoot problems;
  * to collect fees;
  * to improve the Services provided to our Users;
  * to manage risk, or to detect, prevent, and/or remediate fraud or other potentially prohibited or illegal activities, e.g. by checking your location;
  * to detect, prevent or remediate violations of policies or applicable user agreements;

 **We rely on the following lawful bases for personal data processing:**

  * it is necessary to enter into, perform and/or fulfill a contract or an agreement with you;
  * it is our legitimate interest to manage and administer our Services;
  * it is our legitimate interest to protect our customers and our Services against fraud and damage;
  * it is our legitimate interest to develop and improve our Services and attempt to meet our Users’ needs;
  * it is our legitimate interest to understand customer feedback, to respond to customer communications in a consistent way, to ensure our staff deals properly with calls and communications and to train our staff to do so.

### 4\. Information about your using our Services

When you use our Services, we collect information sent to us by your computer, mobile phone or other access devices (whether or not you have registered for our Services). The information sent to us includes but is not limited to the following:

  * unique identification numbers: computer IP address, device ID or unique identifier;
  * geolocation information: time zone setting, city, region, country, and language;
  * computer and connection information, mobile network information;
  * operating system and platform;
  * your device information: device type, browser type and version, and browser plug-in types and versions, hardware and browser settings, app release, app version, device model, manufacturer (brand), operating system, operating system version, OS library version, enable wifi, device screen (width, high, dpi), Bluetooth enable, Bluetooth version;
  * data about Your visit to our website: date and time of visit, products you viewed or searched for, download errors, length of visits to pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), and methods used to browse away from the page, traffic to and from the sites, referral URL, ad data, standard web log data and other information;
  * Bonpay account and marketing preferences.

 **We use your personal data for the following purposes:**

  * to improve the Service by customizing your user experience;
  * to develop new Services;
  * to eliminate issues with the website;
  * to monitor the way our website is used;
  * to measure the performance of the Service and improve their content and layout;
  * to help protect you from fraud and misuse of your personal information;
  * to manage and protect our information technology infrastructure;
  * to provide targeted marketing and advertising, provide service update notices, and deliver promotional offers based on your communication preferences;
  * to provide you with location-based Services, such as advertising, search results, and other personalized content.
  * to communicate with you regarding our Services.

 **We rely on the following lawful bases for personal data processing:**

  * it is our legitimate interest to understand how our website is accessed, how it is used and any problems users have with it across multiple devices, and ensure it is secure;
  * it is our legitimate interest to improve and develop our Services;
  * it is our legitimate interest to promote our Services. If required under applicable law, we will not send you marketing communications unless you first consent to this. You can withdraw such consent at any time by changing your account preferences or contacting us at support@bonpay.com.

### 5\. Communication information

Bonpay collects, monitores, records and/or overhear information from or about you through your contact with us. This information includes:

  * information in your correspondence with us by email, telephone, messaging, texts, on-line chats, via social media, contacting our customer support team or otherwise;
  * whether you’ve clicked on links in electronic communications from us, including the URL clickstream to our website;
  * your results when you respond to a survey;
  * your interactions with Bonpay.
  * your correspondence with us which you provide us while participating in community discussions, chats, or dispute resolutions, or otherwise communicating with us regarding the Services;
  * communicate with you and collect your feedback.

 **We use your personal data for the following purposes:**

  * to provide the Service and customer support;
  * to resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, technical issues;
  * to improve the Service by customizing your user experience;
  * to measure the performance of the Service and improve their content and layout;
  * to provide targeted marketing and advertising, provide service update notices, and deliver promotional offers based on your communication preferences;
  * to poll your opinions through surveys or questionnaires.

 **We rely on the following lawful bases for personal data processing:**

  * it is our legitimate interest to understand how our website is accessed, how it is used and any problems users have with it across multiple devices, and ensure it is secure;
  * it is our legitimate interest to improve and develop our Services;
  * it is our legitimate interest to understand customer feedback, to respond to customer communications in a consistent way, to ensure our staff deals properly with calls and communications and to train our staff to do so;
  * it is our legitimate interest to promote our Services. If required under applicable law, we will not send you marketing communications unless you first consent to this. You can withdraw such consent at any time by changing your account preferences or contacting us at support@bonpay.com.

We do not sell or rent your personal information to third parties for their marketing purposes without your explicit consent. We may combine your information with information we collect from the Third parties and use it to improve and personalize the Services, content, and advertising.

We will ask your consent before using collected information in other purposes.

You can always refuse to supply personal information. In such case we will not be unable to render Services to you.

### 6\. Children

We do not knowingly collect information from children or other persons who are under 16 years old. If you are under 16 years old, you may not submit any personal information to us or subscribe for our Services.

### 7\. Cookies and Similar Technologies

When you visit or interact with our sites, services, application, tools or messaging, our authorized service providers or we may use cookies, web beacons, and other similar technologies for storing information to help provide you with a better, faster, and safer experience and for advertising purposes.

Our cookies and similar technologies have different functions. They are either necessary for the functioning of our Services, help us improve our performance, give you extra functionalities, or help us to serve you relevant and targeted ads. We use cookies and similar technologies that only remain on your device for as long as you keep your browser active (session) and cookies and similar technologies that remain on your device for a longer period (persistent). You are free to block, delete, or disable these cookies. You can manage your cookies and your cookie preferences in your browser or device settings.

When you access our website or use the Service, we (including companies we work with) may place small data files on your computer or other devices. These data files may be cookies, pixel tags, “Flash cookies,” or other local storage provided by your browser or associated applications (collectively “Cookies”). We use these technologies to recognize you as a customer; customize the Service, content, and advertising; measure promotional effectiveness; help ensure that your account security is not compromised; mitigate risk and prevent fraud; and to promote trust and safety across our sites and the Service.

You are free to decline our Cookies if your browser or browser add-on permits unless our Cookies are required to prevent fraud or ensure the security of websites we control. However, declining our Cookies may interfere with your use of our website and the Service.

## HOW WE PROTECT AND STORE PERSONAL INFORMATION

We store your personal information on Bonpay’s secured remote servers within the EEA area. Bonpay staff processes your personal data on the computers in the countries where our facilities are located. We protect your information using physical, technical, and administrative security measures to reduce the risks of loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, and alteration. Some of the safeguards we use are firewalls and data encryption, physical access controls to our data centers, and information access authorization controls.

Only duly authorized staff and partners have access to personal data processing. Bonpay staff is trained on the importance of customer privacy and confidentiality.

We have implemented commercially reasonable technical and organizational measures designed to secure your personal information and other information from accidental loss and from unauthorized access, use, alteration or disclosure. However, we cannot guarantee that unauthorized third parties will never be able to defeat those measures or use your personal information and other information for improper purposes. You acknowledge that you provide your personal information at your own risk.

All electronic personal information is transmitted to other websites through the use of Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology to ensure that your information is fully encrypted and sent across the Internet securely.

An extra layer of security is Two Factor Authentication that is required for every session if set up by the User.

Please note that the transmission of any data over the Internet using personal computers or mobile devices is not completely safe and therefore we cannot guarantee the security of documents submitted to our platform. Any transmission of such documents is at your own risk. As soon as we receive your private information, we implement strict security measures and procedures to avoid unauthorized access from any third party.

## WHY WE SHARE PERSONAL INFORMATION WITH OTHER THIRD PARTIES

The Users will be made aware in most circumstances how and with whom their information will be shared. Bonpay may disclose data without the individual’s consent only in cases expressly prescribed by law. We may share your personal information (including sensitive data) for the purposes indicated below.

### For Services Providing

Bonpay may provide personal information to the processors who perform on our behalf for the purposes of Service providing, administer the use of Bonpay wallet or related services, help to supply, maintain or facilitate our website or our Services or perform any other actions under a signed contract with Bonpay.

### For Transaction Flow

Bonpay may disclose the personal information to the third parties involved in the execution of transactions, including but not limited our banking partners, transactions facilitators, payment service providers, electronic money issuers, card providers, operators of currency exchanges, etc. Also personal information may be provided to persons from whom we receive or to whom we transfer your funds held in Bonpay wallet or card. In such cases, the data provided may include your name, account ID, contact details, or other information needed to promote the reliability and security of the transaction. If a transaction is held, fails, or is later invalidated, we may also provide details of the unsuccessful transaction. Please note that the third parties which your personal data is shared with may be located in other countries where the laws on processing personal information may be less stringent than in your country.

### For Legal Reasons

We may disclose personal information to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims. We may also share such information if we believe it is necessary in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of our Terms of Use, or as otherwise required by law.

In certain situations, we may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including local authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. Bonpay will always ensure the request is legitimate. Bonpay may disclose the personal information in order to comply with anti-money laundering and counter-terrorist financing verification requirements.

### For Statistical Analysis

Bonpay may provide non-personal, summary or group statistics about our customers, sales, traffic patterns, and related website information to reputable third-party vendors, but these statistics will include no personally identifiable information.

### For Business Transaction

We may disclose your personal data in the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets and their advisers. If our business is sold your details will be passed onto the new owners of the business.

### Third Party Websites

If you open Bonpay account directly on a third-party website or via a third-party application, any information that you enter on that website or application (and not directly on a Bonpay website/application) will be shared with the owner of the third-party website or application. These sites are governed by their own privacy policies and you are encouraged to review their privacy policies before providing them with personal information. Bonpay is not responsible for the content or information practices of such third parties.

## CROSS-BORDER TRANSFERS OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

We may transfer your personal data to, and store them at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (EEA) or your country of residence. We may also arrange for your personal data to be processed by staff operating inside or outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our partners. Such staff may be engaged in, among other things, the processing of your payment transactions and the provision of support services. Your personal data can be transferred outside the EEA for the purposes indicated in the section ‘WHY WE SHARE PERSONAL INFORMATION WITH OTHER THIRD PARTIES’. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your personal data is treated securely and in accordance with Bonpay Privacy Policy.

Bonpay is committed to adequately protecting your personal information regardless of where the data resides and to providing appropriate protection for your personal information where such data is transferred across borders, including outside of the EEA.

## DATA RETENTION

Bonpay will not retain personal data longer than is necessary to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected or as required by applicable laws or regulations. We will keep your information for the period when you have Bonpay account, and such further period during which you may bring a claim against us and for us to be able to defend ourselves.

We will also retain your information as necessary to prevent money laundering and to comply with legal, accounting or reporting requirements. We will store your data while you have an account with us and for at least five years after the account is closed, but we may store your data for longer if required for legal claims or other purposes stated in this notice.

Bonpay will retain personal data for marketing purposes for a period of 5 years after termination of the relationship. You will have the opportunity to withdraw your consent to your data processing for marketing purposes using the form in your account.

We will keep information about visitors to our websites (not being customers) for a reasonable length of time that lets us understand how people use our website and any technical issues they have. We will retain this data during 38 months of the User’s last activity.

## USER’S RIGHTS

Bonpay will ensure that the rights of individuals about whom information is held, can be fully exercised under the GDPR. These rights include the rights set out below.

### Right of access by the individual

You can review your personal information at any time by logging in to your account and reviewing your account settings and profile.

You may request by writing to us at support@bonpay.com, details of your information which we hold and the purposes for which it is held. Your request must fall within the definition of personal data provided in ‘WHAT WE COLLECT’ Section.

### Right to rectification

You have the right to have your inaccurate personal data rectified and to have your incomplete personal data completed.

You can add your new address at any time by logging in to your account, Section ‘Settings’ – ‘Address’. You can edit your personal information, email address, phone number, residential address by sending a request at [support@bonpay.com](mailto:support@bonpay.com). To change your identity information or residential address you should upload your documents proving the rectification to comply with KYC and AML regulations. Your documents should fit the requirements indicated in the Section ‘Settings’ – ‘Verification’ in your Bonpay account. Bonpay will refuse to rectify your personal data if you fail to comply the above-mentioned requirements.

Bonpay may restrict the processing of your personal data, including any use of Bonpay Services if you have challenged the accuracy of your data and asked Bonpay to rectify it. Once Bonpay has made a decision on the accuracy of your data, Bonpay will lift the restriction and send you the relevant notification.

### Right to erasure (‘right to be forgotten’)

You have the general right to request the erasure of your personal information in certain circumstances, including where you have withdrawn consent to our using it or we no longer need it in connection with your account or for other legitimate reasons. There are also certain exceptions where we may refuse a request for erasure, for example, where the personal data is required for compliance with law or in connection with claims.

### Right to restriction of processing

You have the right to restrict the processing of your personal data. This means that you can limit the way that Bonpay uses your data. Bonpay will not process the restricted data in any way except to store it.

Please note, however, that all information requested from you is obligatory to be provided by you unless stated otherwise. Should you restrict processing your personal data, we may not be able to provide our product and/or Services to you.

### Right to object

Where we are processing your personal information based on a legitimate interests you may challenge this. However we may be entitled to continue processing your information based on the our legitimate interests or where this is relevant to legal claims. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal information for direct marketing purposes.

### Right to data portability

The right to data portability only applies when:

  * the lawful basis for processing the requested personal data is consent or for the performance of a contract;
  * the processing is carried out by automated means.

### Right not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling

You have the right not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling. You are entitled to require us to ensure that no decision taken by or on behalf of us and which significantly affects you is based solely on the automated processing of your information.

### Right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority

You may lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority.

The Information Commissioner’s Office, [https://ico.org.uk](https://ico.org.uk/).

### Right to withdraw consent

You are authorised to withdraw your consent at any time in those cases where we have requested your consent to carry out the data processing. The withdrawal of your consent will not influence the processing of your data throughout the period when you have validly issued the consent and it will likewise not influence the processing of your data on other legal grounds, if they apply (for example, the adherence to the legal obligations or for the purposes of our justified interests).

If you have given us consent for marketing or if commercial offers are sent to you from us on other justified grounds, you may withdraw your consent at any time using a form in your Bonpay account or contacting us at [support@bonpay.com](mailto:support@bonpay.com).

You can refuse to provide us with the personal data which we request from you. If, however, this involves information which must be compulsorily provided, we will be unable to provide you with the associated services.

### Processing your requests regarding personal data

Bonpay will always verify the identity of anyone making a request regarding personal data before handing over any information by requesting the provision of additional information necessary to confirm the identity of the individual.

We will provide information according to your request, if it complies with all the requirements, within one month of receipt. Bonpay can extend the time to respond by a further two months if your request is complex or we have received a number of requests from you.

The information about your personal data will be provided to you free of charge unless your request is manifestly unfounded or excessive or if you request further copies of your data following a request. In such case, you may be charged a reasonable fee of £10 per subject access request for the administrative costs of complying with the request as permitted by the GDPR.

## USER’S CONSENT

I hereby give my explicit consent and agree:

  * to provide required personal data to Bonpay to be able to use any of Bonpay Services;
  * to keep my personal data accurate and up-to-date, and notify Bonpay about the changes of my personal data;
  * to receive communication from Bonpay.

I hereby give my explicit consent to Bonpay:

  * to collect my personal data through the means described in this Policy;
  * to process my personal data for marketing mailout and communications;
  * to process my sensitive personal data;
  * to transfer my personal data outside the European Economic Area or my country of residence;
  * to share my personal data with the third parties as indicated in this Policy;
  * to use cookies or other means to store information.

## CONTACT DETAILS

If you would like to contact us with any queries or comments regarding our Privacy Policy, please contact us using the contact details below:

Data Protection Officer: [dpo@bonpay.com](mailto:dpo@bonpay.com).
